amway.my 2016-03-15

# AMWAY (MALAYSIA) SDN BHD PRIVACY POLICY

Amway (Malaysia)  Sdn Bhd recognises that your privacy is very important to you and to most people. Our Privacy Policy is detailed below and we suggest that you read it thoroughly. This policy may change from time to time and all changes will be posted on this Web Site so please check back periodically. We collect personal data only if you are or become an ABO and we use that information mainly to help us understand your needs so that we may better service them.

The Personal Data Protection Act 2010, which applies to all companies and firms established in Malaysia, was introduced by the Government to regulate the processing of personal data in commercial transactions.  The Act requires us to inform you of your rights with regards to your personal data that is collected and processed, and the purpose of such processing.  It also requires us to obtain your consent to the processing of your personal data.

I.          **Objective** : 

The policy aims at identifying the standard requirements on collecting, operating, maintaining, protecting, disclosure, retaining, and archiving and distributing the personal information of AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd employees and ABOs.

II.         **Scope** : 

The policy is applicable to those who are AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd employees, ABOs and the third parties who process these personal data in the name of AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd.

III.        **Definition** : 

·         **Personal data** is any information in any format (electronic or paper) that identifies an individual in respect of commercial transaction. It includes obvious information like names, addresses and email addresses but it also includes biometric information such as fingerprints or tissue samples. If it can be used to identify or locate you – alone or with other information – then it is personal information. 

1)    Gender, age and birth date

2)    Family address and telephone number

3)    Employment information, personal education, performance and training information

4)    Spouse’s information

5)    Information of family income and expense

6)    Personal hobbies

·         **Sensitive personal data** consists of those elements of personal data that require extra privacy and security protections. For example, any information about a person’s health or condition of  health subject, his political opinions, his religious beliefs or other beliefs of similar nature. Government issued identifiers (such as Employee Provident Fund or Income Tax numbers) are also sensitive personal data:

1)    Personal information record/criminal record/ court summons record

2)    Race, faith, political viewpoint, philosophical faith

3)    Member of trade union

4)    Health information: disease history, disability 

5)    Bank account information, computerized national identity card number

6)    Nationality, citizenhood information

IV         **Policy Statement**

The **Privacy Policy** says how we respect both our staff and ABO’s Personal Data interests: 

·         We provide NOTICE to individuals about how their personal data is used. 

·         We obtain CONSENT for the processing of personal data.

·         Where appropriate, we provide individuals with ACCESS, the opportunity to review and correct personal data held by AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd . 

·         We only USE and TRANSFER personal data for AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd business purposes, in accordance with our notices, our **Privacy Policy** and applicable Malaysian laws. 

·         We PROTECT personal data with appropriate safeguards. 

·         The personal data processed will not be KEPT longer than necessary

**1.     ****General**

******How WE COLLECT PERSONAL DatA**

We collect Personal Data from you in various ways and at several different points. We may collect your Personal Data on one of our web sites, by telephone, facsimile, when you complete and submit an application form to become a ABO.  
Wherever possible we collect Personal Data directly from you. There may, however, be occasions where we collect your Personal Data from someone else. For example, where you make an application in joint names. 

If you provide Personal Data to us about another person, we rely on you to have made, or make them aware that you will, or may, provide their information to us and the kinds of third parties we may provide it to and the relevant purposes we and the third parties will use it for and how they can access it. If you have not done, or will not do these things, you must tell us before you provide the relevant Personal Data. 

We may share the Personal Data you provide through the various means above with other Amway- related entities and/or trusted business partners with whom we collaborate, as well as those that provide services to our Site. Where we engage non-affiliated third-party agents or contractors, we require them also to observe the intent of this Privacy Policy.

From time to time, we may provide Personal Data in response to court order, subpoena, or government investigation. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful. We may release Personal Data when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves.

Should Amway (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd or its related entities merge with or be acquired by another business entity, or its respective assets be acquired, you should expect that we would share some or all of your Personal Data to companies assuming the role of serving you and other users of our Site.

**2.     ****ABOs**

If you are a ABO, you will receive advice and information from your own personal business advisory team and support network consisting of your sponsoring ABO and upline organisation. To allow such communication, we may share your contact information with your sponsoring ABO  and upline organisation. They have agreed not to share your information with any non-affiliated third parties, and are obligated to observe the intent of this Privacy Policy. In the ordinary course of supporting your business, information about you and your orders might be shared with your sponsoring ABO  and immediate upline ABO. You have the opportunity to let us know, however, if you do not want any Personally Identifiable Information shared beyond your immediate upline ABO.

**3.     ****Your Choices**

      Your permission is always secured first. We will not use or share the Personal Data collected in ways unrelated to the purpose for which you provided the information, including those described above, without providing you a choice whether to permit any such unrelated uses.

**4.    Accessing and Correcting Your Information**

We take reasonable measures to ensure that any Personal Data we collect is accurate, current, complete, and reliable for its intended use. If you wish to update or otherwise correct Personal Data you have provided to us, you may edit your information online after completing registration, or contact us as described in the "Contact Us" section, below, and we will assist you. ****

**5.    Changes To This Statement**

      Any updates or changes to the terms of this Privacy Statement will be posted here on our Site and the date of the newest version posted below.  Please check back frequently, especially before you submit any Personal Data at our Site, to see if this Privacy Statement has changed.   If any changes materially affect the use of Personal Data previously provided to us, we will obtain your consent prior to the retroactive application of any material changes. By using our Site, you acknowledge acceptance of this Privacy Statement in effect at the time of use.

**7.     ****Contact   Us **

If you have any concerns about our use of your Personal Data or wish to access and correct your personal data or about this Privacy Policy , please post or send an e-mail to:

**Postal address:          **

| 

Sales Division

(ABO Records)

AMWAY (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd 

P.O.Box 84

Jalan Sultan

46710 Petaling Jaya

Selangor Darul Ehsan  
  
---|---  
  
**Email address:**

|   
  
We will make every reasonable effort to address your concerns and remedy any problems you bring to our attention.
